Atsuko Tominaga

+43-677-64054156 | tominaga_atsuko@phd.ceu.edu | atsukotominaga.com | github.com/atsukotominaga

Last updated: April 13, 2021

Research Interests

My research interests are in the field of cultural transmission and social learning. I am investigating how learning from/with others has contributed to delivering cultural knowledge and skills to younger generations. I use an experimental method adapted from Cognitive Psychology and focus on the interaction between experts and novices in musical skill acquisition. I am currently working on how expert pianists modulate their performance to teach musical expressive techniques and how such modulations could be beneficial to novice learners.

EDUCATION

Central European UniversityAustriaPhD candidate in Cognitive ScienceSep 2017 - PresentUniversity of YorkUnited KingdomMaster of Research in PsychologyOct 2016 - Jan 2018Kyoto UniversityJapanBachelor of Arts in Education (specialised in Psychology)Apr 2009 - Mar 2013

Academic Work Experience

Technical Assistant, Coordinator

Kokoro Research Center, Kyoto University

Apr 2016 - Aug 2016

- Ran experiments with Eyelink 1000 (SR Research)
- Organised research events for public
- Created necessary documents for research travel and funds

Secretary of Director, Coordinator

Kokoro Research Center, Kyoto University

Jun 2013 - Jun 2014

- Assisted international visiting researchers
- Organised research events and special undergraduate lectures
- Wrote summary reports of research events for lay audience
- Created necessary documents for research travel and funds

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Kokoro Research Center, Kyoto University

 $May\ 2011 - Nov\ 2012$

- Ran experiments with Eyelink 1000 (SR Research)
- Created visual stimuli using Adobe Photoshop

PUBLICATIONS

Scott-Phillips, T., **Tominaga, A.**, & Miton, H. (in press). Ecological and psychological factors in the cultural evolution of music. *Behavioral and Brain Sciences*.

Ueda, Y., **Tominaga, A.**, Kajimura, S., & Nomura, M. (2016). Spontaneous eye blinks during creative task correlate with divergent processing. *Psychological research*, 80(4), 652-659.

POSTER PRESENTATIONS

Tominaga, A., Sebanz, N., & Knoblich, G. (2021). The Sound of Teaching Music: Experts' sound modulation for novices. 11th Society for Tokyo Young Psychologists (STYP11), Japan.

Tominaga, A., Sebanz, N., & Knoblich, G. (2019). The Sound of Teaching Music: Experts' sound modulation for novices. 12th International Conference of Students of Systematic Musicology (SysMus19), Berlin, Germany.

Tominaga, A., Sebanz, N., & Knoblich, G. (2019). The Sound of Teaching Music: Experts' sound modulation for novices. 8th Joint Action Meeting (JAM8), Genoa, Italy.

SKILLS

Languages: Japanese (native), English (fluent), German & Hungarian (elementary)

Programming: R, Python, Max MSP

Extracurricular activities: CEU Student Union representative (2017-2019), Music Cognition Reading Group (2018-)